Nicholas Bely

Front end Developer

- Profile

An engineer with 7 years of diverse engineering experience looking to transition fully into the software development field. A strong advocate of self-learning and diligently working to solve problems, but also seeking guidance when the opportunity arises. Equipped with a great foundation for entering the field, and eager to learn in an industry setting and become a well-rounded, valued asset.

Project History

Turg-Bot Discord Game

June 2020 — Present

REPO

- Developing full-scale fan-game in Node.js via Discord API, utilizing MongoDB game/user data storage w/Mongoose and parsed data stream results from a forked 3rd party battle simulator
- Working on React web application for displaying user profiles and interactable/customizable user event-logs

Personal Portfolio

July 2021 — Present

LIVE | REPO

- Practiced self-guided Angular web app concept design and implementation, along with employing responsiveness
- Learned how to implement and adapt UI components from Material.io library and organize page layouts with fxFlex API

Angular Course Project: Recipe Book

December 2020 — July 2021

LIVE | REPO

- Completed course project demonstrating fundamental and advanced knowledge and practice of Angular concepts, user interface design with Bootstrap, and firebase deployment
- Gained understanding of and ability to create and utilize modules, components, directives, routing, observables, forms, pipes, http requests, and user authentication

Front End Developer Volunteer at Comau LLC, Southfield, MI

January 2021 — May 2021

 Created a summary dashboard for an Angular 9 web application utilizing the ngx-admin template and plotly graphing library

Education

Bachelor of Science in Biomedical Engineering with Honors, Wayne State University, Detroit

September 2012 — May 2016

Details

(586) 854-9715 nicholas.bely@gmail.com

Skills

Typescript | Angular 2+

Javascript | Node.js | React.js

noSQL (MongoDB) | mySQL

HTML5 | CSS3 | Accessibility

UI/UX Tools | Bootstrap | Material.io

Python | Machine Learning

Git | GitHub

Agile and Scrum

Links

Portfolio LinkedIn GitHub

Courses

Angular: The Complete Guide, Udemy

December 2020 — July 2021

Python Data Structures, Coursera

July 2020 — August 2020

Other Work Experience

Controls Hardware Engineer at Comau LLC, Southfield, MI

November 2016 — Present

- Supported electrical and pneumatic hardware design and installation efforts in four different Powertrain and two Body-in-White assembly lines from OEM's inclusive of Ford, FCA, Cummins, and Lucid
- Oversaw successful integration of vendor equipment by organizing vendor quotes and lineups, pushing design reviews and material procurement, and handling problem resolution

Co-op Engineer at Joyson Safety Systems, Sterling Heights, MI

May 2016 — November 2016

- Designed a proof-of-concept testing apparatus for infrared facial recognition including: NX CAD design, hardware integration, prototyping, and software development.
- Configured autonomatronic head movement tests via an Arduino serial interface, acquired and processed data in Visual Studio with C before delivery to facial detection algorithm.

Lead Programmer at Functional Optical Imaging Lab, Detroit, MI November 2014 — May 2016

- With awarded research grant, contributed extensively to software, electrical, and mechanical development of two cutting edge microscopy systems in a new Wayne State research lab
- Led development of multiple LabVIEW programs featuring producer/consumer queue architectures for handling real-time data acquisition and image processing of a photoacoustic microscope, published work in two conference papers

References

References available upon request